EPISODE 8: WELCOME TO THE DEFENSE FORCE
（第8集：歡迎加入防衛隊）
I'll be the one to neutralize No. 8.
怪獸8號就由我來討伐
What do I do?
我該怎麼辦？
I can't use my fists against Vice-Captain Hoshina!
我不能對保科副隊長出拳
That seemed to work.
刀刃劃傷你了呢
No, I won't survive this if I try to hold back!
不行，如果有所保留，我是打不過他的
He's so quick, I can't harden my body to protect myself fast enough!
他的攻擊速度太快，我來不及硬質化
He may not be stronger, but he's a hell of a lot faster than the humanoid Kaiju!
只論動作，他比剛才的人形怪獸快多了
The first time I saw Kikoru move, I thought she was incredible.
第一次看到琪歌露的動作時 我就覺得她很不得了
But...
可是
He's on a whole other level!
他又是另一個不同的境界了
He's not even moving like a human!
這根本不是人類做得到的動作！
But I dodged that!
我明明閃開了啊
What is this? Some kind of slashing attack I can't see?
這是怎麼回事？看不見的斬擊？
Core located.
發現核心所在
Not that I'm human, either.
不過我也不算是人類
Now that I've done it, I can tell that regenerating uses a lot of my stamina!
試過之後才知道，復原會消耗大量體力
I can't take too many hits like that!
要是再被他多砍幾刀就糟了
Wait, seriously?
喂！喂！不會吧？
I'm not exactly joking around here.
我可是很認真地在進攻耶
He's probably at least Fortitude 8.0.
牠的怪獸規模大概超過8.0
That'd make him a Daikaiju.
是可以被歸類為大怪獸的個體
But what's this weird feeling I'm getting from this fight?
但我從剛才就覺得有哪裡不太對勁
Well, it doesn't matter.
也罷
Those invisible slashes...
無形刀刃的…
And a double attack!
二連擊
No.
不對
The double attack was a decoy!
是佯裝成二連擊！
Mist Slasher.
幻霞襲
A triple attack?!
是三連擊？
Gotcha.
砍中你了吧
The blade...
刀刃…
The blade's stuck!
動彈不得
That was close.
好險
That was stronger than I expected, but...
威力超乎我的預料，不過…
After he saw my core, I knew he'd aim for me there!
在他看見核心的位置之後 我就知道他會瞄準這裡
No!
糟了
Yikes. I let it get away.
唉，被牠跑走了
Reporting.
報告
Kaiju No. 8 has escaped.
怪獸8號已逃走
Kaiju No. 8.
怪獸8號
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
Now leave the rest to me!
接下來就交給我吧
Is it really okay for me to believe in him?
我可以繼續相信他嗎？
I'm back...
我回來了
Sorry, I must've worried you.
抱歉，讓你擔心了
I wasn't worried!
誰擔心你了啊？
And I have more than a thing or two to say to you...
不說這個了，我有好多話要跟你…
Hey!
等等！
Sorry... I let it get away.
抱歉，我讓牠逃走了
The one who hurt you...
就是打傷你的那傢伙
I-I don't care.
我無所謂啦
I'll kill it myself.
我會自己幹掉牠
Hey, where are you going? You're in terrible shape.
等等，你要拖著這副身體去哪裡？
Ichikawa and Iharu were horribly injured... I have to go.
市川跟伊春傷勢嚴重，我得去找他們
And even if you went, what could you do?
你去了又能幹嘛？
They'll be fine.
他們一定沒事的
The Defense Force is starting to use Kaiju regeneration in its tech, too.
防衛隊已開始針對怪獸的修復能力 進行技術轉移了
You should worry about yourself instead!
你倒不如先擔心你自己吧
Not only did the other officers see you,
不只被其他隊員發現
you made contact with Vice-Captain Hoshina!
還接觸了保科副隊長
They could easily find some clue that leads straight to you!
就算被抓到什麼把柄也不奇怪
It's rare to see you this down.
真難得看你這麼沮喪呢
Cripes. You've caught me in a really embarrassing spot.
被你看見我不堪的一面了
I'll take a photo to remember it by.
我來拍張照留念吧
Please don't!
別這樣！
So, was Kaiju No. 8 strong?
所以，怪獸8號的威力很強大嗎？
I'm assuming it's a Daikaiju.
牠可能是大怪獸
That would make it the first one since Fukuoka five years ago.
那牠就是福岡那隻怪獸以來 五年沒出現的大怪獸了
Fortunately, there've been no casualties due to No. 8 these past few months.
幸好這幾個月都沒出現怪獸8號的犧牲者
It doesn't seem to be the type to attack people indiscriminately.
看來不像是會隨意襲擊人類的類型
Yeah, that's the strange feeling I had...
對了，那個不對勁的感覺
Why did No. 8 attack my weapon instead of me?
8號為何沒有攻擊我 而只是打掉我的武器？
Nothing about that battle made sense.
戰鬥時我就一直覺得很奇怪
The way it moved and reacted...
牠的動作和反應
It was more like fighting a human than fighting a Kaiju.
與其說是怪獸，不如說像是在跟人對戰
For now, get some rest.
總之，你先休息一下吧
I'll take care of this.
剩下的由我來接手
No matter what type of Kaiju it is,
無論是哪種類型的怪獸
it's our job to neutralize it.
都要趕盡殺絕
Well, she's right there.
她說得沒錯
Roger.
瞭解
Captain! Vice-Captain!
隊長！副隊長！
You're too loud, Ikaruga.
你太大聲了吧，斑鳩
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Sorry. I learned something I thought you should hear.
抱歉，我收到了值得注意的情報
The Kaiju that attacked Furuhashi and Ichikawa
襲擊古橋和市川的怪獸
appears to have been the same humanoid type that appeared at the exam site.
應該和測驗會場出現的人形怪獸是同一隻
When they found it,
但他們發現怪獸時
it had a human form.
牠有著人類的樣貌
Hey!
喂！
Hey, are you deaf?
喂！你聽見沒有？
Out of the way!
快點讓開
Hey, say something!
喂，你說句話啊
Breaking news.
新聞快訊
After the latest incident, the Defense Force
有鑑於這次的事件
has designated the humanoid-type that appeared at the exam site and Sagamihara
防衛隊已將出現在 測驗會場及相模原的人形怪獸
as a long-term neutralization target,
列為長期討伐目標 並將其代號指定為怪獸9號
Now, how do I kill Kaiju No. 8?
接下來，該怎麼幹掉怪獸8號呢？
Oh dear, oh dear.
唉呀，不行
I'll need to remain hidden until I get used to this body again.
在適應這個身體之前 我又得藏匿一段時間了
He's awake.
他醒了
Hey.
喲
You awake, partner?
你醒啦，我的搭擋
Senpai, I'm glad you're okay.
前輩，幸好你沒事
That's my line, dummy.
那是我的台詞吧，笨蛋
Also... thank you.
還有，謝謝你
For saving me and Iharu-kun.
你救了我跟伊春
Why are you thanking the old dude?
你為什麼要跟大叔道謝？
Iharu-kun's in the same room?!
伊春你也在啊？
It was Kaiju No. 8 that saved us, right?
救了我們的不是怪獸8號嗎？
Well, he found the Yoju reproductive organs,
畢竟他發現了餘獸的增殖器官
and that was a huge help, right?
這個功勞不小吧？
Oh, good point.
喔，確實如此
Thanks, old dude!
謝啦，大叔
S-Sure thing!
不客氣
Why'd the Kaiju save us, though?
不過，那隻怪獸為什麼要救我們啊？
He was so strong. He knocked No. 9's head clean off!
牠超強的，一拳就打飛9號的頭
For a Kaiju, he was pretty damn cool!
雖然是隻怪獸，但是超帥氣的
I wish you could've seen him!
真想讓你們也見識一下
Hey, why are you blushing, old dude?
大叔你在害羞個什麼勁啊？
Blushing?
害羞？
He's got the same dumb look on his face he always does!
這傢伙本來就是一臉蠢樣
Very true!
好像是這樣沒錯
We're so lucky it was Iharu-kun...
幸好我們面對的是伊春
You don't need to hit me so hard.
你用不著揍得這麼大力吧
FURUHASHI & ICHIKAWA CONGRATULATIONS ON LEAVING THE HOSPITAL
（古橋、市川，恭喜出院）
Congratulations on leaving the hospital!
恭喜你們出院！
W-What's this?
這是？
A celebration for our first successful mission!
首場任務的慰勞會
We were waiting for you to get out of the hospital.
我們等到你們出院才舉辦的
Okay, let's get started.
那就開始吧
Your course of A6-grade marbled Japanese Black Wagyu beef!
這是A6等級的黑毛和牛霜降套餐
A6?!
A6？
Is there an A6?!
有這種等級嗎？
*THERE IS NOT
（沒有）
We could never serve less than the finest at a party organized by Haruichi-sama.
在陽一少爺擔任總召的餐會 我們不能端出丟臉的餐點
I remember asking for the cheapest course.
我記得我訂的是最划算的套餐耶
You can pay the standard prices.
結帳時我們只會收取標準價格
Really? Lucky us!
真的嗎？太幸運了
Just who is Haruichi?
陽一是何方神聖啊？
What?
什麼？
You didn't know when you asked him to put this together?
你不知道他的來歷，就找他當總召嗎？
That's right.
嗯
He's the heir to Izumo Technologies,
他是國內最大間的對怪獸兵器製造商
the largest anti-Kaiju arms manufacturer in the country.
出雲科技的小開
The place that makes the Defense Force suits?
製造防衛隊戰鬥服的那間公司？
Yeah. He's got way more wealth than even my family.
沒錯，連我家的財力都比不上
So that's why you asked me to find a place?
所以你才會拜託我找店嗎？
That's right.
沒錯
You said you wanted everybody to get a good meal, right?
因為你說想讓大家吃好料
And he's perfect for the job, huh?
他就是最佳人選，對吧？
Yeah.
是啊
So yeah, excellent job on your first mission.
總之，第一個任務辛苦了
You don't get many days when all your batchmates
跟同期的隊員同時一起，不用值勤 這種機會相當難得
So have a lot of fun!
大家盡情享受吧
Cheers!
乾杯！
Yeah, this is so good!
超好吃的
...blew his head right off! It was amazing!
牠的頭一擊就被打飛，超厲害的
I've never seen everybody looking so happy.
我第一次看到大家這麼開心
Thank you for putting this together.
謝謝您安排這場餐會
Don't speak too soon, Ichikawa.
你太天真了，市川
The show's about to start.
好戲現在才要開始呢
What do you mean?
您的意思是？
And you're too busy trying to show off to help your team!
你這個人太愛搶風頭了
And you make everything personal!
而且還摻雜太多私人情感
You're the one person on this team who has zero right to say that to me!
這個的話，你最沒有資格說我吧
I don't count, 'cause I'm just that damn good!
我不一樣啊，畢竟我可是身懷絕技
Guys, don't fight...
別吵架
You always do things your way and neglect the basics.
你太我行我素了，往往忽視基礎動作
And you do things so by the book, you can't keep up when we work together!
你才是太忠於基礎動作 攜手攻擊時都慢半拍
I have to slow myself down, you know.
都是我在配合你耶
These guys too?
這邊也在吵？
So anyway, Izumo-san...
比起這個，我說出雲先生啊
You sure you guys' suits ain't defective?
你們家的戰鬥服會不會太弱了？
I couldn't even defeat a single one of those jerks!
我一隻怪獸都打不倒耶
Draw out more of its power, then.
你先喚醒更多戰力吧
Not you too, Senpai!
連前輩也開始了
Hey, you're with the comms team, right?
話說，通訊小組啊
We kept losing communications during the mission!
作戰途中，老是容易斷訊
You're the ones who kept going inside interference areas without telling us!
還不是因為你們擅自跑進障礙物裡
We've told you that if you give us advance notice, we can work it out!
早就說過只要事先通知一聲 我們就會予以協助了
Oh no! It's everywhere I look...
糟糕，到處都在吵架
But isn't this...
不過，這樣…
You've noticed, huh?
你發現了啊？
They're all talking about the mission now.
不知不覺間，大家都在談論任務的話題
After their first mission, they've all seen what they're lacking.
經過第一個任務之後 大家都看見了自己的不足
That's right. It's not just me.
也對，不是只有我而已
Everybody wants to be stronger.
大家都想變得更強
What did you say, asshole?
你說什麼啊你？
Show some respect for your elders!
也該尊重一下長輩吧？
I only respect people stronger than me.
我只尊重比我強的人
All right, it's on!
好啊！
I'll show you who's boss!
來比啊，看我怎麼讓你啞口無言！
I'm tired of listening to your whining, you know.
別以為我忍著聽你講，你就可以囂張！
That's my line, jerk!
這句話是我要說的吧
You don't listen, do you, girl?
你這女人真是聽不懂人話耶
You've got no right to say that to me!
你才沒資格說這句話咧！
It's a yearly tradition.
這真是每年的傳統呢
We were so happy you reached out to us, young master.
我很高興能接到少爺您的聯絡
I thought I'd never see you again.
我還以為沒機會再見到您了
Don't say that, Dojima-san.
你別這麼說，堂島先生
I just wanted to make sure everybody had a nice meal.
我只是想讓大家吃點美食而已
So, about your father...
請問您和令尊…
I haven't talked to him since then.
在那之後，我們就沒說過話了
I see.
這樣啊
I'm sorry for worrying you.
抱歉，讓你操心了
Dojima-san, today's meal was incredible.
堂島先生，今天的餐點也非常美味喔
Did he hear that?
被他聽到了嗎？
Bathroom.
我要去廁所
I guess he's not the nosy type.
不過，他也不是會多管閒事的類型
Okay, calm down, everybody.
好，大家安靜
Time to make an announcement.
差不多該來宣布那件事了
Announcement?
哪件事？
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
You saved a lot of lives during the mission,
多虧你在作戰時的貢獻，讓損害大幅降低 這點值得肯定
So you're getting promoted to full officer.
你可以升格為正式隊員了
Welcome to the Defense Force's Third Division.
歡迎加入防衛隊第3部隊
Yes!
太好了！
Senpai!
前輩！
You did it, old dude!
太好了呢，大叔
Don't call me that!
別叫我大叔
Time to give him a victory toss!
把他拋起來慶祝一下
Great idea!
好主意
Grab him, guys!
大家抓住他
You help out, too!
快來幫忙
Don't drop him!
別讓他摔下來
It's a good night.
真是個愉快的夜晚
If I can stop us from losing a single person, I want to.
真希望不會少了任何一個人
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
好耶…好耶！
Yeah, I agree.
嗯，是啊
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
As of today, as of this moment, you are no longer a cadet,
今天即刻起，將你由候補隊員
but a full-fledged Defense Force officer.
正式升格為防衛隊員
I swear to give everything I have to the fight.
我宣誓將全力以赴，挺身作戰
A-Anyway, I'll be going...
那麼，我就告辭了
Don't get too excited.
你先別高興得太早
You're a long way from being able to fight by my side.
想與我並肩作戰，你還差得遠了
So Mina does remember!
米娜果然還記得
Yeah, just you wait, Mina!
嗯，你等著看吧，米娜
Give me fifty push-ups for failing to address a superior by their title.
直呼長官名諱 罰你做完伏地挺身50下再離開
I did it again!
我又不小心說出來了
Kaiju No. 8
怪獸8號
and No. 9 need to be discussed at HQ, which requires my presence.
以及9號的事情，還要等我去總部處理
Whew...
嚇死我了
I've put Vice-Captain Hoshina in charge, so ask him about the paperwork.
剩下的我已經吩咐保科副隊長了 詳細的手續你就去問他吧
Roger!
瞭解
And... it was Hoshina who recommended you for full officer.
另外，推薦你成為正式隊員的也是保科
Of course, it only happened because of your success in the last battle.
當然是基於你在上一場戰鬥的表現
The vice-captain...
副隊長他…
Live up to his expectations.
別辜負他的期望
Roger!
瞭解
I guess that's enough for today.
今天就到這邊吧
I don't want another lecture from the vice-captain.
不然又要被副隊長盯上了
The training room?
訓練室？
At this hour?
都這個時間了？
Who forgot to turn the lights off?
是誰忘了關燈啊？
The vice-captain? What's he doing?
副隊長？他在做什麼？
Mental imagery training?
意象訓練？
But the way he's moving...
看他的動作…
He's not just doing ordinary training.
這不是普通的意象訓練
He's recreating his battle with me!
他是在重現跟我交戰時的情況
Oh, Kafka?
卡夫卡，是你啊
You're here way too late again.
你又摸到這麼晚了啊
What about you? Why are you here so late?
我才想問副隊長 都這麼晚了還在做什麼啊？
Working out a strategy for No. 8.
這是怪獸8號的對策
So I can slice him in half with a single strike next time I see him.
這樣下次遇見牠時，才能讓牠一刀斃命
I screwed up at the start, you know.
是說，一開始我就搞砸了
If I'd gone all in right off the bat, I could've chopped his head off.
要是一開始就使出全力 我早就把牠的頭砍掉了
And...
而且
If I'd used technique six instead of technique five,
要是我用的不是刀伐術5式，而是6式
I could've sliced him and his core into ribbons.
早就能把牠連同核心一起大卸八塊了
You're getting way too scared.
你嚇成這樣太誇張了吧
No normal officer could handle that thing.
牠不是普通隊員能對付的對手
And No. 9's probably close to as strong.
9號的威力恐怕也差不多
So...
所以…
I've gotta handle 'em myself.
牠們得由我來解決
He really is amazing.
他真的有夠厲害
He's not just trying to keep civilians safe, but us, too!
不只是市民，他也打算保護我們這些隊員
Vice-Captain!
副隊長
I'll do my best to be able to help in the fight.
我會努力讓自己發揮戰力的
Don't get so cocky, fool!
你少自以為是了，蠢蛋
I don't expect a guy with 1% power to be helpful!
我才不指望解放戰力1%的傢伙 能夠提供戰力咧
B-Bye...
抱…抱歉了
But, well...
不過…
You can have 1% of my expectations.
我對你抱有1%的期待
I'm heading back to the office.
我要回辦公室一趟
You get to sleep.
你快去睡吧
Roger!
瞭解
Initiate descent.
開始降落